International Fur and Leather Workers Union Records 5676
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Lewis, Leo (organizer: Newark, Buffalo, New Haven, Toronto, Gloversville), 1938-1941 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Lind, Robert (organizer: Newark), 1937-1939 (Box 11, Folder 34)
- Los Angeles Sanatorium, 1936-1940 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  re emergency campaign to raise funds for the sanatorium; and routine.
- Lucchi, Pietro (General Secretary-Treasurer), 1930-1936 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  correspondence re Local 2 and 3 (Brooklyn) re agreements, 1930-32; wages due Locals 2 and 3 members by Robert Gabbe, Inc.; "Brief presented by Harold Goldstein, Vice-President (Fur Workers) at the Policy Hearing on the Subject of Employment Provisions Before the NRA, January 30, 1935," 5 p.; legal document (subpoena) in re Lucchi vs. American Fur Liners Contractors Association; income tax forms; letter from Local 79, San Francisco, re strike in Oakland; and routine.
- Lucchi, Pietro, 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  letters from several locals re affiliation with the CIO; "Memo for P. Lucchi, 10/4/37" re Local 2's victory; correspondence with President Green, Matthew Woll, and many others thanking them for their appearances in court in his behalf re violation of anti-trust laws; legal papers re case against Lucchi, Locals 2 and 3 and others; and routine.
- Lucchi, Pietro, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  continued correspondence re case against Lucchi; correspondence re sending letters to President Roosevelt asking for clemency from AFL, American Labor Party and many others; correspondence re Lucchi receiving Fur and Leather Worker publication while in prison and rejection by Bureau of Prisons; many letters of support; and misc.
- Lucchi, Pietro, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  Bulletin No. 1, February 28, 1940 - "Trial of 25 IFLWU Officers and Members on Alleged Violation of Sheman Anti-Trust Law" 2 p.; several letters from Lucchi announcing his release after 7 1/2 months and thanking them for support; and misc.
- Lucchi, Pietro, 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  Income tax forms and misc.
- Lucchi, Pietro (Box 11, Folder 41)
  2 p. "The International Union Label"; 2 p. "Resolution Submitted by Locals 2 and 3"; misc. financial information; 6 p. "Convention Report by President Pietro Lucchi"; 3 p. "Fellow Workers!" apparently an address before the Easton Fur Workers presenting them a charter; 5 p. "Report of the 56th Annual Convention of the AFL at Tampa, Florida" by delegates P. Lucchi, Samuel Mindel and Harry Begoon; 1 p. "A Message of Greetings from the General Executive Board of the International Fur Workers Union," greeting by Lucchi for New York Furriers Joint Council, 25th Anniversary; 2 p. memorial for Brother Cabri; an address, 2 p., to Local 88; 4 p. "Looking Ahead"; 3 p. memorial for Hyman Kalmikoff; 4 p. "Our Fight in Winnipeg"; and other misc.
- Lucchi, Pietro (Box 11, Folder 42)
  includes additional addresses, statements and releases by and about Lucchi; and misc.
- L General, 1934-1936 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  broadside and form letter re strike of Laundry Drivers Union, Local 810, (IBT), 1936; and routine.
- L General, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 44)
- L General, 1938-1940 (Box 11, Folder 45)
- L General, 1941-1954 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  includes a report and form letter, 1947 from Labor Sports Federation; letter from Latin American Research Bureau to Feinglass re execution of Guatemalans by firing squads of President Castillo Armas; and routine.
- Malain, Arthur L., 1941 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  reports on organizing activities, routine correspondence.
- Marcantonio, Vito (Congressman), 1947 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  letter to B. Gold requesting contribution for political campaigns, 6/11/47.
- March of Labor, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  letter form J. Steuben, editor, to B. Gold re the future of March of Labor and the danger of the magazine "going under", 1/5/54; galley proof and routine.
- Markewich and Null, 1936-1940 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  testimony of William Green re Pietro Lucchi case before U. S. Senate Committee on Military Affairs, 12/2/37; and routine.
- Markewich and Null, 1936-1940 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Maurice, M., 1947 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  routine correspondence to B. Gold from M. Maurice, Secretary-General of the Federation Nationale Ouriere des Cuirs et Peaux, France.
- May Day, 1937-1954 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  broadsides; history of May Day; form letters; news release; and routine.
- Metz, Julius, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  article "Statement of Eugene J. Bernstein on Behalf of the Independent Raw Fur Merchants of Louisiana," 6 p., no date; extensive correspondence re organizing in New Orleans, Louisiana area; legal document - Morris Steinberg and Julius Leslie Steinberg, A Louisiana Partnership (Steinberg and Co.) vs. Southern Fur Trappers' Branch of the IFLWU; letter to B. Gold, 7/6/47, re effect of Taft-Hartley passage on organizing effort; and misc.
- Metz, Julius, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Metz, Julius, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Metz, Julius, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Metz, Julius, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Metz, Julius, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Mid-Southern Farmers Union, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Milinery Workers Union (Local 24), 1936-1937 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  letter to Pietro Lucchi from Bella Altshuler, Secretary, 3/31/37; re discrimination against women workers; broadside; telegram, 8/2/37, re jurisdiction to Pietro Lucchi from President Zaritsky of Local 24.
- Millstone, Harry, 1940-1942 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Millstone, Harry, 1940-1942 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Mindel, Samuel (Brooklyn, New York), 1938-1941 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  handwritten letter, no date, to Pietro Lucchi re suggested amalgamation of several locals vs. establishment of a Joint Board; and routine.
- Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, International Union of (IUMMSW), 1947-1966 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  Report of Canvassing Committee, 1946; statement presented to the CIO Committee by the IUMMSW, "The Story of Disruption in the IUMMSW-CIO ... a History of John J. Driscoll and His Associates" 1947, 46 p.; correspondence re a secessionist group in the IUMMSW; newletters; article; letter and attached "Special Report on the Trial of Brother Clinton Jencks," 4/2/54; agreement of affiliation between the United Steelworkers of America (USA) and the IUMMSW, 11/18/66, 14 p.
- Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, International Union of (IUMMSW), 1947-1966 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Monck, Harry (Newark, New Jersey), 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Monck, Harry (Newark, New Jersey), 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 22)
- Mooney, Tom, 1936-1937 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  correspondence and form letters re defense of Tom Mooney.
- Multila, E. R. (Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan), 1942 (Box 12, Folder 24)
- M General, 1936-1954 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  form letters; article re McCarthyism, 12 p., no date; and routine.
- M General, 1936-1954 (Box 12, Folder 26)
- M General, 1936-1954 (Box 12, Folder 27)
- M General, 1936-1954 (Box 12, Folder 28)
- Naidenoff, Tom, 1937-1939 (Box 12, Folder 29)
- Nation Associates, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  correspondence re Palestine; "The Palestine Problem," confidential report on the work of the Nation Association at the United Nations, 28 p., 1947; "Could the Arabs Stage and Armed Revolt Against the U. N.?", 1947, 77 p.
- National Negro Labor Council, 1937-1954 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  summary proceedings of a United Nations conference on minority problems, 1947, 3 p.; reports; broadside; and routine correspondence.
- National Surety Corp., 1936-1939 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  routine bonding correspondence.
- National Women's Trade Union League of America, 1937-1947 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  form letters and routine correspondence.
- Negro Labor Committee, 1935-1939 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  form letters and routine.
- New Leader, 1936-1937 (Box 12, Folder 35)
- New York Fur Trimming Manufacturers Association, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  correspondence with William Green, President, AFL, re relations between the International Fur Workers' Union and the New York Fur Trimming Manufacturers Association.
- Novick, Paul (editor, The Fur Worker), 1937-1939 (Box 12, Folder 37)
- Novick, Paul (editor, The Fur Worker), 1937-1939 (Box 12, Folder 38)
- Novick, Paul (editor, The Fur Worker), 1937-1939 (Box 12, Folder 39)
- N General, 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  letter from Jacob Billikopf, Executive Director National Coordinating Committee For Aid to Refugees and Emigrants Coming From Germany, to Lucchi re a concern about the propaganda being spread about Local 70 (Greek local) and the International racial issue; and routine.
- N General, 1938-1942 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- N General, 1945-1954 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Obarski, Herbert (organizer: Wilmington, Delaware), 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Oberther, Oscar (organizer: Pennsylvania), 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Oberther, Oscar (organizer: Pennsylvania), 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- O'Toole, Larry (organizer: St. Louis), 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- O General, 1936-1954 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Palestine, 1946-1947 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  form letters and misc. pamphlets.
- Parr, Philip (organizer: Rochester, New York and Elkland, Pennsylvania), 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Parr, Philip, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Parr, Philip, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Pam, Philip (organizer: Chicago), 1942 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Paul, Herman (organizer), 1937-1945 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  correspondence re discrimination against active union members; 3 p. report on Middletown meetings and activities; re organizing activities in Local 72 (Washington, D.C.); letter of resignation due to family ill health and complimenting Gold on his leadership ability; 4 p. report on Greek situation (Local 70); 7 p. report of H. Paul re Local 130 and Local 92; 2 p. "Hollander Locals Go to the Polls."
- Perron, F. X. (organizer: Quebec), 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Perron, F. X. (organizer: Quebec), 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Perron, F. X. (organizer: Quebec), 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Perryman, Robert (organizer: Ridgway, Pennsylvania), 1942 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Pershing, George (organizer - Peabody, Massachusetts and Williamsport, Pennsylvania), 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Pershing, George (organizer - Peabody, Massachusetts and Williamsport, Pennsylvania), 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Planning Board, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  National Federation of the Fur Industry, Inc. - includes minutes of meetings, correspondence and recommendations re proposal for an industry-wide planning board in the fur industry, between Gold and various associations and companies.
- Pocketbook Workers Union, 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  requests for financial assistance during strike in Chicago; and routine.
- Press Releases, 1927-1938 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  from AFL Committee to Reorganize the New York Fur Workers Union, 1927; the Fur Workers Union; (some of these releases in draft form) covering many subjects some of which include problems of officials of Local 70, A. Hollander agreement, convention preparations, AFL investigation re Communism.
- Progressive Party, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  correspondence, form letters, memos re activities.
- Prompt Press, 1937-1939 (Box 13, Folder 25)
- P General, 1928-1936 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  letter with attachments to Frances Perkins re deportation of Dominick Sallitto and Vincent Ferrero; and routine.
- P General, 1937-1938 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  letter from a Seattle fur worker to Ben Gold, 8/29/37, thanking him for his loyalty and praising him and the International; form letters, etc. re People's Lobby, Inc.; and routine.
- P General, 1939-1942 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  letter and attachments, 8/18/41, re People's Institute of Applied Religion, Little Rock, Arkansas; and routine.
- P General, 1945-1954 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  letter to A. Clayton Powell from B. Gold and his reply re a racial remark made by Congressman Rankin; correspondence and from letters re Palestine; invitation to attend "Frances Perkins Dinner of Recognition"; telegrams re terrorism in Spain.
- Q General, 1936-1940 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  correspondence re Queens Premier Fur Dressing Co. in need of employees (Local 2), contract states within 48 hours or they look to open market; and routine.
- Reiss, Morris, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  reports and extensive correspondence re strike in Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada; other routine correspondence.
- Reiss, Morris, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Reiss, Morris, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Relief Germany, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Rest Home, 1945-1947 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  correspondence re purchase of Camp Jackson, White Lake, New York; resolution re the Ben Gold Fur Workers Camp Association; article, diagrams and correspondence re location and construction.
- Rest Home, 1945-1947 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Retirement Fund, 1954-1960 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  9 p. proposed retirement plan, 1954; letter from H. Cammer, attorney, to Leon Straus, Joint Board Fur Dressers and Dyers Union re IFLWU retirement fund under merger with Amalgamated, 12/29/54; form letters; schedules; proposed constitutional amendments; and routine.
- Retirement Fund, 1954-1960 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Retirement Fund, 1954-1960 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Retirement Fund, 1954-1960 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Retirement Fund, 1954-1960 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Ricco, A. A., 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1936-1945 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  routine correspondence to President Roosevelt.
- Rosner, Alex (New Brunswick, New Jersey), 1940 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Rothenburg, Harry I. (Detroit, Michigan), 1937-1941 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Roy, Albert (Montreal, Canada), 1936-1943 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  report, routine correspondence.
- Roy, Albert (Montreal, Canada), 1936-1943 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Roy, Albert (Montreal, Canada), 1936-1943 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Roy, Albert (Montreal, Canada), 1936-1943 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Russell, John (Elkland, Pennsylvania), 1941-1942 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Russell, John (Elkland, Pennsylvania), 1941-1942 (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Russian War Relief, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- R General, 1936-1947 (Box 14, Folder 23)
- R General, 1936-1947 (Box 14, Folder 24)
- R General, 1936-1947 (Box 14, Folder 25)
- Sbar Corporation, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 26)
- Schulman, Jack, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Shames, H., 1937 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  routine correspondence; report on organizing campaign in Washington D.C.
- Shinbane, A. M., 1937-1942 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  routine legal correspondence - Winnepeg, Canada.
- Skin prices, 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  correspondence re removal of 20% Fur Tax.
- Social Security, 1937-1942 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  Receipts and forms; form letters; copies of tax returns re Social Security; pamphlet "Proposed Changes in the Social Security Act," 1939, 29 p.; news releases.
- Social Security, 1937-1942 (Box 14, Folder 32)
- Social Security, 1937-1942 (Box 14, Folder 33)
- Spence, Windels, Walser, Hotchkiss and Angell, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  routine correspondence with Kenneth Walser.
- Starr, Joseph (Toronto, Ontario, Canada), 1939-1942 (Box 14, Folder 35)
- Starr, Joseph (Toronto, Ontario, Canada), 1939-1942 (Box 14, Folder 36)
- Stein, Gordon (Seattle, Washington), 1937-1939 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  reports on organizing activities in Seattle, Washington and routine correspondence.
- Strike, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  correspondence between William Green, President, AFL, and Harry Begoon, General Secretary-Treasurer, re agreements renewed, left wing workers who are antagonistic to AFL, suspension of Communist group in Local 30 (Boston).
- Strike, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  correspondence re upcoming strike situation by the Communist group, physical assaults on members, etc.
- Strike, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  3 p. release "A Fur Workers Strike - What For," June 6, 1929, an official statement of the International; releases and misc.
- Strike, 1928-1929 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  correspondence between an attorney and Harry Begoon re debt owed and Begoon's explanation of poor financial state of the union; "Report of the Activities of the Furriers Joint Council for 12 Months--December 1928-November 1929," unpaged; releases; announcements; broadsides; agreement; 3 p. "Official Information on Passing Events in Our Union From the International Fur Workers Union of the U. S. and Canada" by Harry Begoon; and misc.
- Strike General, 1925-1926 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  correspondence between AFL officials and Fur Workers officials re New York situation; strike declared; letters of support; financial audit of Joint Board Furriers Union; scab work; Isidor Winnick, acting General President to Schactman, General President, and B. Gold, Chairman, Strike Committee, re trying to find out where and when the Committee is meeting; beatings; Communist element; and misc.
- Strike General, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  appeals for financial assistance by union members; members beatings and threats; funds of International exhausted.
- Strike General, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  correspondence; excerpts of meetings; financial report of the Joint Board of Furriers Union, etc.
- Strike Winnipeg, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  correspondence, telegrams, clippings re strike.
- Strike Support, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  3 letters requesting financial support from International Fur Workers.
- Suroff, Max (Vice-President), 1923-1924 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  correspondence re charges against Suroff for slander and opposition of the International.
- Syme, M. Herbert (attorney), 1935-1937 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  re certificate of registration for union label and other misc and routine.
- S General, 1924-1936 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  correspondence re Scottsboro Boys Defense Committee requesting contribution; and routine.
- S General, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  correspondence and memo from Rev. Dr. D. de Sola Pool re alleged discrimination of Greek Fur Workers in New York City; form letter, publication, broadsides re Sheep Shearers' Union No. 1, Butte, Montana; correspondence re arrest and imprisonment of Morris Stein, for union activities; additional correspondence, release, etc. re Scottsboro Defense Committee; and misc.
- S General, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- S General, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- S General, 1941-1945 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- S General, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 17)
- S General, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Textile Workers Organization Committee (TWOC), 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  4 p. letter to Lucchi from Water Cook, TWOC, re the finances and accounting system of the International; re strike support at Horner Brothers' Woolen Mills, Eaton Rapids, Michigan; strike at Bigelow-Sanford Carpet; and routine.
- Thompson, Hugh, 1940-1942 (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Trade Union Educational League (Box 15, Folder 21)
  9 p. "Report of National Conference"; 2 p. "Some Questions to the International Officers."
- Trade Union Veterans Committee, 1951-1954 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  form letters, legal documents, broadside, etc. re McCarthyism.
- Trades and Labor Congress of Canada, 1936-1938 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  re per capita tax and attendance at convention.
- T General, 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  form letters, programs, etc. re Tamiment Economic and Social Labor Conference; Norman Thomas Campaign; Committee for the Defense of Civil Rights in Tampa; Toronto Labor Lyceum; correspondence with Daniel Tobin, President, Teamsters, re jurisdiction of truck drivers in fur industry; correspondence and financial statements with Leon Tobias, Designer and Builder of Business Interiors.
- T General, 1938-1940 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  correspondence with Tobacco Stemmers and Laborers Industrial Union re strike in Richmond; with Trades and Labor Congress of Canada re Fur Workers suspension of membership.
- T General, 1942-1954 (Box 15, Folder 26)
- Unemployment Fund, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  7 p. mss. and misc. re working out an unemployment plan.
- Unemployment Insurance - New York State, 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  form letters, forms, payroll record, etc.
- Unemployment Insurance - New York State, 1938-1940 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  forms, form letters, etc.
- Union Label Committee, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  photos of members including President Lucchi stamping skin with union label; routine correspondence, form letters, minutes, 3 p. mss.
- United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers (UE), 1953-1954 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  newletters, form letters, releases, correspondence re Taft-Hartley Hearings, Butler Bill and other anti-labor legislation; 3 p. minutes of first meeting of Provisional Coordination Committee of Five Unions on Brownell-Butler Act, resolutions.
- United Fur Manufacturers Association, Inc. (Greek Fur Workers Union, Local 70), 1938 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  correspondence with Nick Mousmoules, Impartial Chairman of the Association re various decisions and violations of agreements; and misc.
- United National Clothing Collection, Inc., 1945 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  re nationwide drive to collect used clothing for overseas relief.
- U. S. Department of Labor, 1936-1938 (Box 15, Folder 34)
- U General, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  letter from United Rubber Workers President re strike against Goodyear.
- U - General, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 36)
- U General, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 37)
- U General, 1940-1942 (Box 15, Folder 38)
- U General, 1945-1947 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  invitation and programs for inauguration of U. S. President Roosevelt.
- Vafiades, John, 1937-1939 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Van Der Heeg, T., 1927-1928 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  correspondence re AFL's internal struggle and Communist participation; and Russian Clothing Workers Union resolution.
- Van Nordsten, Joe (Chicago, Illinois), 1940-1941 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Veterans, 1947-1954 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  statement of policy for local IFLWU Veterans Committees; form letters.
- V General, 1936-1947 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  form letters; letter to B. Gold from L. Vassil, United Garment Workers Union in Winnipeg, Canada, re garment workers in Canada, joining the CIO and relations with the "general office" 5/25/37; and routine.
- War Emergency Board of the Fur Industry, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- War Labor Board, National, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Winnick, I. (Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada), 1926-1928 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  copy of a letter to Joint Council, IFWU re internal struggle in AFL and Communist infiltration; correpondence re suspension of I. Winnick; and routine.
- Winnipeg Trades and Labor Council, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  letter to P. Lucchi from J. B. Graham, Secretary of the Council, reporting on a conference of fur manufacturers with representatives form the Council 1/29/37; and correspondence re relationship between fur manufacturers and the Council in Winnipeg.
- Winogradsky, Joseph, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  correspondence re "unhealthy situation" in Toronto, Ontario, Canada; and routine.
- Witt and Cammer, 1945-1947 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  legal correspondence re trapping in Louisiana; arrests at Endicott- Johnson, in Endicott, New York; outline of professional services rendered in Endicott, New York; court brief re Brunson vs. North Carolina 12/30/47; and routine.
- Wolf, Samuel (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), 1939-1940 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Women's Auxiliary, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  correspondence re obtaining a charter form the International; form letter; and a copy of charter.
- Workmen's Circle, 1932-1940 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- World Trade Union Conference, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  "Report of the CIO Delegates to the World Trade Union Conference," 14 p.; news release.
- Wright's (Chester M.) Labor Letter, 1935-1940 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  scattered issues and form letters.
- W General, 1936-1954 (Box 16, Folder 17)